Marc Gaede Papers, 1910-1999.: Finding Aid C1436
Manuscripts Division
- Robert Sundance Working Files, 1910-1998; Sundance, Robert, 1927-1993; 21 boxes
  In 1975, Sundance sued the city and county of Los Angeles to demand better treatment of alcoholics arrested for public inebriation. Sundance v. Los Angeles Municipal Court was the beginning of a two-decade legal battle known as the "Sundance Case," in which a judge ruled in 1978 that improvements must be made to ensure the constitutional rights of those arrested for public drunkenness. Sundance appealed to the Second District Court of Appeal in 1981 and the California Supreme Court in 1987 with the aim of decriminalizing public drunkenness entirely; while these appeals were ultimately unsuccessful, and the United States Supreme Court declined to hear his case, Sundance's legal battle led to a dramatic decrease in arrests in Los Angeles and an increase in treatment options for homeless people struggling with alcoholism. His activism played a major role in popularizing the perception of alcoholism as a disease and public health issue rather than a crime, as well as in increasing treatment-based alternatives to incarceration for alcoholics in the Los Angeles area and beyond. After entering into recovery himself, Sundance became the executive director of the Indian Alcoholism Commission of California in 1979, lobbying to improve alcoholism treatment programs in Los Angeles County, with a focus on how alcoholism affected indigenous communities.
  - Sundance Book Interviews and Drafts, 1991-1995; 7 boxes
    Arranged to reflect the process of composition.
    These materials document from start to end the composition of Robert Sundance's biography, which was written as a collaborative effort of Robert Sundance and Marc Gaede. The earliest materials are sound recordings on audiocassette tapes of Sundance narrating his life story, which include an oral history interview of Sundance facilitated by Gaede, as well as tapes that Sundance made of his own singing, story-telling, and free association. These are followed by interview transcriptions made from some of the tapes, early corrected chapter drafts that Gaede composed based on the recordings of Sundance, and full drafts of the book in both paper and digital form.
    - Sound Recordings, 1991 February 5-1992 April; 2 boxes
      Fifty-four audiocassette tapes containing recordings of Robert Sundance. Most are undated.
      - Sundance #1 A&B, 1991 February 5; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #2 A&B, 1991 February 5; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #3 A&B, 1991 February 5-27; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #4, 1991 February 27; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #5, 1991 February 27; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #6, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #7, 1991 March 21; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #8, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #9, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #10, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #11, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #12, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #13, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #14, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #15, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #16, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #17, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #18, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #19, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #20, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #21, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #22, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #23, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #24, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #25, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #26, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #27, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #28, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #30, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #31, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #16 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #17 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #18 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #19 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #20 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #21 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
      - Sundance #22 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance #23 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance #24 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance #25 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance #26 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance #27 Copy, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance #30 Backup, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance #31 Backup, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance Chapter 1, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance Chapter 18, 1992 April; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance Conclusion, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance Prison Tapes, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Early Sundance Music and Talk, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance Music and Talk, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Robert Sundance Talking and Music, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Rita Ann McLaughlin, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
      - Sundance, undated; 1 box (Box 34)
    - Interview Transcriptions, 1991 September 8; 1 box
      Transcriptions were done by Karen Ostrom. Most are undated.
      - Interview Transcription 1, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 1)
      - Interview Transcription 2, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 2)
      - Interview Transcription 3, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 3)
      - Interview Transcription 4, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 4)
      - Interview Transcription 5, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 5)
      - Interview Transcription 6, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 6)
      - Interview Transcription 7, 1991 September 8; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 7)
      - Interview Transcription 8, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 8)
      - Interview Transcription 9, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 9)
      - Interview Transcription 10, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000840, Folder 10)
    - Early Chapter Drafts, 1991 June 17-1992 February 15; 2 boxes
      - Sundance Abstract/Outline, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 1)
      - Rehabilitation Draft 1, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 2)
      - Los Angeles Draft 2, 1991 November 15; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 3)
      - Los Angeles Draft 3, 1991 December 20; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 4)
      - Los Angeles Draft 5, 1991 December 23; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 5)
      - Los Angeles Draft 6, 1991 December 27; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 6)
      - Los Angeles Draft 1B - New Revision, 1992 February 5; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 7)
      - Pocatello Draft 1, 1991 October 31; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 8)
      - Pocatello Draft 2, 1991 November 5; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 9)
      - Pocatello Draft 1B, 1992 January 21; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 10)
      - Prison Deer Lodge 1, 1991 September 1; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 11)
      - Prison Draft 2, 1991 September 4; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 12)
        With Sundance's Revisions 9-8-91
      - Prison Draft 3, 1991 September 8; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 13)
      - Prison Draft 4, 1991 September 25; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 14)
      - Prison Draft 6, 1991 December 14; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 15)
      - Prison Draft 7, 1991 December 20; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 16)
      - Prison Draft 1B, 1992 January 16; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 17)
      - Parole Drafts 1 and 2, 1991 September 1-1992 January 16; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 18)
      - Miles City Draft 1, 1991 August 10; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 19)
      - Miles City Draft 2, 1991 August 15; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 20)
      - Miles City Draft 3, 1991 August 22; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 21)
      - Miles City Draft 4, 1991 September 1; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 22)
      - Sundance's Miles City, 1991 September 7; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 23)
      - Miles City Draft 5, 1991 October 7; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 24)
      - Miles City Draft 6, 1991 November 24; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 25)
      - Miles City Draft 1B, 1992 January 14; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 26)
      - Billings, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 27)
      - Billings Draft 1, 1991 July 16; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 28)
      - Billings Draft 3, 1991 August 9; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 29)
      - Billlings - Sundance's Revisions, 1991 August 8; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 30)
      - Billings Draft 4, 1991 September 6; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 31)
      - Billings Draft 5, 1991 September 8; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 32)
      - Billings Draft 6, 1991 October 3; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 33)
      - Billings Draft 7, 1991 October 12; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 34)
      - Billings Draft 8, 1991 October 26; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 35)
      - Billings Draft 9, 1991 November 24; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 36)
      - Billings Draft 1B, 1992 January 12; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 37)
        Also includes A Self-Guided Tour of Old Montana Prison
      - Minneapolis Draft 1, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 38)
      - Minneapolis Draft 2, 1991 July 10-11; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 39)
      - Minneapolis Draft 3, 1991 August 17; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 40)
      - Minneapolis Draft 4, 1991 October 21; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 41)
      - Minneapolis Draft 5, 1991 November 24; 1 folder (Box B-000841, Folder 42)
      - Rapid City and DTs Draft 1, 1991 July 1; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 1)
      - Rapid City and DTs Draft 2, 1991 July 4; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 2)
      - Rapid City and DTs Draft 3, 1991 July 16; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 3)
      - Rapid City and DTs Draft 4, 1991 July 28; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 4)
      - Rapid City and DTs Draft 5, 1991 August 3; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 5)
      - Rapid City and DTs Draft 7, 1991 October 1; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 6)
      - Rapid City and DTs Draft 8, 1991 October 11; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 7)
      - Rapid City and DTs Draft 9, 1991 November 24; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 8)
      - Rapid City - Sundance's Revisions, 1991 July 4; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 9)
      - Military Draft 1, 1991 June 22; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 10)
      - Military Draft 2, 1991 June 22-July 5; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 11)
      - Military Draft 3, 1991 July 10; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 12)
      - Military Draft 4, 1991 July 17; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 13)
      - Military Draft 5, 1991 July 28; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 14)
      - Military Draft 6, 1991 August 3; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 15)
      - Military Draft 8, 1991 October 9; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 16)
      - Military Draft 9, 1991 November 24; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 17)
      - Military - Sundance's Revisions, 1991 June 22-July 5; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 18)
      - Early Years Draft 1, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 19)
      - Early Years Draft 2, 1991 June 17; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 20)
      - Early Years Draft 3, 1991 June 30; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 21)
      - Early Years Draft 4, 1991 July 9; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 22)
      - Early Years Draft 5, 1991 July 16; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 23)
      - Early Years Draft 6, 1991 August 3; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 24)
      - Early Years Draft 7, 1991 October 1; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 25)
      - Early Years Draft 8, 1991 November 24; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 26)
      - Early Years Draft 9, 1991 December 28; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 27)
      - Early Years - Sundance's Revisions, 1991 June 17-July 16; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 28)
      - Protest Draft 2B, 1992 February 15; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 29)
      - Legal Protest Draft, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 30)
      - Phoenix Draft 1B, 1992 January 23; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 31)
      - The Franklin Draft 1B, 1992 January 28; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 32)
      - Back to Billings Draft 1B, 1992 January 17; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 33)
      - Conclusions, Various Drafts, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 34)
      - Miscellaneous Draft Fragments, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000842, Folder 35)
    - Full Book Drafts, 1992; 1 box
      - Draft 1B Original, 1992 January 2; 1 folder (Box B-000843, Folder 1)
      - Draft 1B, 1992 January 2; 1 folder (Box B-000843, Folder 2)
      - Original Draft 2B, 1992; 1 folder (Box B-000843, Folder 3)
      - Draft 2B Copy, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000843, Folder 4)
      - Draft 2B Copy, 1992 January 29-30; 1 folder (Box B-000843, Folder 5)
      - Manuscripts No. A, 1992 February 5; 1 folder (Box B-000843, Folder 6)
      - Preliminary Review Copy F, 1992; 1 folder (Box B-000843, Folder 7)
    - Digital Drafts, 1991 June 15-1995 January 9; 1 box
      Consists of digital files extracted from thirteen 3.5" floppy disks. These text-based documents largely comprise both chapter and full drafts of the Robert Sundance biography, but there are also a small number of files containing digital copies of related agreements and publicity documents. Titles refer to handwritten labels on each floppy disk; item numbers refer to the order in which disks were processed.
      Original order was preserved.
      Digital files are accessible on a computer in RBSC's reading room.
      - Sundance Material 1, 1992 February 17-1992 March 1; disk001; 18 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 2, 1992 February 18-March 1; disk002; 16 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 3, 1991 July 7-1992 April 4; disk003; 24 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 4, 1993 March 27-April 2; disk004; 18 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 5, 1992 February 17-April 19; disk005; 26 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 6, 1992 February 29-June 2; disk006; 27 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 7, 1993 March 31-September 14; disk007; 17 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 8, 1991 July 4-1993 September 18; disk008; 17 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 9, 1991 July 7-1992 February 16; disk009; 5 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 10, 1991 July 7-1993 September 18; disk010; 16 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 11, 1991 June 15-November 5; disk011; 4 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Material 12, 1991 October 4-1992 January 18; disk012; 3 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
      - Sundance Final, 1993 February 22-1995 January 9; disk013; 37 digital files; 1 box (Box 35)
  - Legal Documents, Research, and Publicity, 1963-1995; 10 boxes
    Original file groups were preserved, and unorganized materials were roughly grouped by topic.
    Consists of legal documents and correspondence related to cases Robert Sundance pursued against the city and county of Los Angeles regarding the treatment of people arrested for public intoxication, his research materials on topics including tribal law and alcoholism, and clippings and publicity regarding Sundance's case and other tribal rights issues across the country, particularly as related to the Sioux Nation. Robert Sundance often compiled these materials (a mixture of originals and photocopies) topically into binders and folders, incorporating legal documents, correspondence, and reports gathered during his research, along with related publicity and press clippings. There are clippings and copies of magazine and newspaper articles from both national and local news sources, as well as several video recordings of television segments. Sundance often annotated the clippings he collected with his own critiques and notes regarding information omitted from news stories. Loose materials found alongside these files contain much of the same mix of content and provide insight into Sundance's extended fight against the California legal system and the ways in which he managed the depiction of his life story in the public eye.
    - Superior Court of the State of California for the County of Los Angeles Documents, 1975-1979; 1 box
      - Superior Court Judgment, 1978 March 17; 1 folder (Box B-000844, Folder 1)
      - Superior Court Memorandum Opinion, 1977 December 5; 1 folder (Box B-000844, Folder 2)
      - Superior Court Proposed Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law, 1978 January; 1 folder (Box B-000844, Folder 3)
      - Superior Court City Defendants' Memorandum, 1978 May 15; 1 folder (Box B-000844, Folder 4)
        Full title of document is "City Defendants' Memorandum of Points and Authorities in Opposition to Plaintiffs' Motion for New Trial, to Modify the Judgment and to Vacate the Judgment."
      - Superior Court Complaint for Injunctive and Declaratory Relief and Petition for Writ of Prohibition and Writ of Mandate, 1975 July 9; 1 folder (Box B-000844, Folder 5)
      - Superior Court Plaintiff's Pre-Trial Brief, 1977 July 12; 1 folder (Box B-000844, Folder 6)
      - Superior Court Various Documents, 1975-1979; 1 folder (Box B-000844, Folder 7)
      - Superior Court Press Releases and Publicity, 1975-1978; 1 folder (Box B-000844, Folder 8)
    - District Court of Appeal of the State of California Second Appellate District Documents, 1982-1983 May 26; 1 box
      - District Court Appeal from the Superior Court of Los Angeles County, 1982 April 23; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 1)
      - District Court Appendix of Statistical Sources, 1982; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 2)
        Full title of document is "Appendix of Statistical Sources in Support of Request for Judicial Notice Pursuant to Evidence Code 452(d and h) and 459."
      - District Court Appellants' Petition for Rehearing, 1983 April 12; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 3)
      - District Court Petition for Hearing, 1983 May 9; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 4)
      - District Court Answer of Petitioners Robert Sundance, et al., to City of Los Angeles' Petition for Hearing, 1983 May 26; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 5)
      - District Court Appellants' Opening Brief, 1982 April 23; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 6)
    - Supreme Court of the State of California Documents, 1986 December 31-1987 February; 1 box
      - Supreme Court Remittitur, 1987 February 5; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 7)
      - Supreme Court Answer to Petition for Rehearing and/or Modification, 1987 January; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 8)
        Includes copies of some related correspondence.
      - Supreme Court Opinion by the Court, 1986 December 31; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 9)
      - Legal Correspondence, 1987 January-February; 1 folder (Box B-000845, Folder 10)
        Consists of legal correspondence of Timothy B. McFlynn, which was originally filed with Sundance court documents, primarily regarding B-Wagons used to transport public inebriates and legal precedents set by the Sundance case.
    - "Publicity and Facts", 1975-1982; 3 folders (Box B-000846, Folder 1-3)
    - "Struggle, Survival, Sovereignty", 1976-1979; 1 folder (Box B-000846, Folder 4)
    - "Crossroads of Destiny", 1975-1985; 2 folders (Box B-000847, Folder 1-2)
    - Sundance Case, 1975-1980; 3 folders (Box B-000847, Folder 3-5)
    - Sundance Case, 1980-1982; 1 folder (Box B-000848, Folder 1)
    - Alcoholism, 1976-1982; 2 folders (Box B-000848, Folder 2-3)
    - Robert Sundance Professional Correspondence, 1976-1980; 1 folder (Box B-000848, Folder 4)
      Consists primarily of Robert Sundance's correspondence pertaining to his work with the Harbor Light Rehabilitation Center for Alcoholism and the Indian Alcoholism Commission of California, along with some related clippings and materials related to the Sundance case.
    - Indian Alcoholism Commission of California Documents, 1975-1986; 1 folder (Box B-000848, Folder 5)
    - Timothy B. McFlynn Correspondence, 1980-1986; 1 folder (Box B-000848, Folder 6)
    - Legal Correspondence Regarding Sundance Case Discovery, 1977; 1 folder (Box B-000848, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence Regarding Sundance Case Legal Counsel, 1982-1983; 1 folder (Box B-000849, Folder 1)
    - Social Justice, Indian Alcoholism Commission of California Work, 1975-1986; 1 folder (Box B-000849, Folder 2)
    - Order Denying Writ of Habeas Corpus, 1971 March 31; 1 folder (Box B-000849, Folder 3)
      Multiple copies.
    - Habeas Corpus and Certiorari Petitions, 1971-1975; 1 folder (Box B-000849, Folder 4)
    - Alcoholism Research and Correspondence, 1979-1983; 1 folder (Box B-000849, Folder 5)
    - Reports on Alcoholism as Illness, 1971-1992; 1 folder (Box B-000849, Folder 6)
    - Printed Materials on Alcoholism, 1979-1981; 1 folder (Box B-000849, Folder 7)
      Some are annotated.
    - Ethnography of Indian Drinking Patterns in California Project, 1980; 1 folder (Box B-000850, Folder 1)
    - Public Justice Foundation File on Sundance Case, 1984-1986; 1 folder (Box B-000850, Folder 2)
    - Clarence Darrow Foundation Award Brochures, 1979; 1 folder (Box B-000850, Folder 3)
    - Hanta Yo Episode 3 Script, 1980; 1 folder (Box B-000850, Folder 4)
    - American Indian Activism Clippings, 1979-1980; 1 folder (Box B-000850, Folder 5)
    - Sioux Nation Sovereignty Notes and Research, 1977-1979; 1 folder (Box B-000850, Folder 6)
    - Sioux Tribe vs. United States Docket 74 and 74B, 1972-1974; 1 folder (Box B-000850, Folder 7)
    - Treaties and Agreements of the Sioux Nation, 1974; 1 folder (Box B-000850, Folder 8)
    - Report on Standing Rock Sioux Tribal Justice System, 1980; 1 folder (Box B-000850, Folder 9)
    - American Indian Self-Determination and Sovereignty Research, 1975-1976; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 1)
    - Ogala Sioux Black Hills Case, 1974-1992; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 2)
    - Bill of Particulars from Ogala Sioux to Richard Nixon, 1973; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 3)
    - Pat McLaughlin Testimony Before Indian Policy Review Commission, 1976 May 8; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 4)
    - Interstate Congress for Equal Rights and Responsibilities, circa 1980; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 5)
    - Joint Statement of Claims Counsel for the Missouri Sioux Nation Before the Subcommittee on Indian Affairs, 1974 August 8; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 6)
    - Lakota Nation Treaty Council Meeting Transcript, 1976 March 17; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 7)
    - Remember Wounded Knee Press Kit, 1973; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 8)
    - Granville House vs. DHS, Minnesota, Memorandum Opinion, 1982; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 9)
    - "The Phoenix", 1980; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 10)
    - "Rodeo Pictures", 1966; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 11)
    - Tao Te Ching, 1972; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 12)
      Bound copy.
    - Miscellaneous Printed Books, 1963-1990; 1 folder (Box B-000851, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Publicity and Clippings, 1975-1995; 3 folders (Box B-000852, Folder 1-3)
    - Television Segments on Sundance Story, 1991 December 10-1993 May 21; 1 box
      Consists of three VHS videotapes containing video recordings of television segments about Robert Sundance and the Sundance story on both NBC and local Los Angeles television news stations.
      - NBC Sundance Original, 1993 May 21; 1 box (Box 32)
      - Sundance on Columbus Cable #3 L.A., 1991 December 10; 1 box (Box 32)
      - Robert Sundance Story on NBC N.N., undated; 1 box (Box 32)
  - Robert Sundance Personal and Family Materials, 1910-1998; 4 boxes
    Arranged by material type.